<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MAGAMBO Gatete Elie</title>
    <description>Data Scientist/Software Engineer</description>
    <link>http://eliethesaiyan.github.io</link>
    <atom:link href="http://eliethesaiyan.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>The essence of learning through repetitive rewarding steps</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I just had one of those AHA! moments when you understand fundamentals of something through some simple example.
Learning,why is it so hard to learn something;lots have been said about learning something new and how to master it in considerably small amount of time but with little emphasis on that one has to finally find suitable way of learning something either by finding his own pace,or following other people examples which mostly don`t work out so well if dont apply a sense of indivuality on it.
My case is little similar to what i have just said above by learning to play a game called &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/jelly-squares/id974529966?mt=8&quot;&gt;Jelly Squares&lt;/a&gt;
My friend was playing level 34 and insisted that i give it a try,which i did and failed terribly.In my opinion the game was not intuitive how to play it and also 34 was a no starting point.He changed the level to 22 but still it was undoable(its kind of puzzle) and we decided to start from an easy level,14.
He left me with his phone and went to play pool with some other friends while i was  still trying to figure out how  atleast to pass level 14.
Long story short i did pass level 14 and continued to other levels which little by little became more easier because i was getting used to the game.He kept checking which level i was on until i reached 34 which was where we started.He joined and also contributed to the play ,within 2 min we had already figured out how to pass it and it was fairly simple considering how  hard it seemed before we played it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well,what struck me the most during this phase is how starting with easy level helped a lot in solving a complex cases(Complex is relative,maybe easy for you!).
I am a kind of person who like to jump preliminaries and go straight to the main problem but after having this experience i realized how starting fairly easy would drastically change how you understand the big picture of anything you want to learn.I also noticed how motivated i became when i passed each level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bet for some people this is just a default procedure,take a task put it into small steps and solve one by one(I do it too but not in learnings something new) but some  others they just want to make sure once the work starts,it gets done as soon as possible which lead them to spend a lot of time and fair amount of energy that could be saved if it was done in small steps.
My learning style is like the latter, if i want to learn chapter 3,i will take a glance at chapter one,read chapter two and study chapter three  which leads me to go back and forth  to chapter 2 and also chapter 1 with also fair amount of googling.
I guess this experience was an eye opening for me on how i should attack enormous task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its not bad to dedicate your strength to something but its very important to understand that there are things that take time no matter how hard or  bad you want to accomplish them and learning something is one of them.Once you fully go through the whole process of doing something correctly it will be  easy to go through  them over again and build on top of your past experience and mistakes to attempt even more complex tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but not least,if it wasn&lt;code&gt;t for that guy i wouldn&lt;/code&gt;t even know that the game exist even if i knew about it would have been more difficult to play it alone;here i am trying to make an analogy to having a mentor in what we do.We all need someone to guide us through our baby steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sayonara&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://eliethesaiyan.github.io/essence-of-learning</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eliethesaiyan.github.io/essence-of-learning</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Python cheatsheet Lookup List</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided to compile a cheatsheet  of useful links that helped me to undestarnd or fix a problem so it will be easy for me to check it whenever i forget how i fixed it.
The links are mostly answers to questions similar to ones i had that includes some examples as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/2681243/how-should-i-declare-default-values-for-instance-variables-in-python&quot;&gt; instantiating class variables&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/26653401/typeerror-object-takes-no-parameters-but-only-in-python-3&quot;&gt; Misspelling &lt;strong&gt;init&lt;/strong&gt; or indenting it wrongly&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will keep updating the list. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sayonara&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://eliethesaiyan.github.io/python-cheatsheet</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eliethesaiyan.github.io/python-cheatsheet</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fixing grub</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In December 2015 i ve broken my laptop dual boot installation due to broken system depencies caused by shifting location.For those familiar with ubuntu,i  over messed with sources.list file and i couldn`t track some of the changes i ve made and ended up loosing the bootloader of of my laptop.
I got luck recovering it was pretty easy.I booted on live CD&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JA MATTA&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://eliethesaiyan.github.io/fixing-grub</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eliethesaiyan.github.io/fixing-grub</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello Jekyll,Github Pages world</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;i`ve never seen importance of blogging(I read many blogs) until the day i realized that not only blogging is to communicate and get feedback with/from others but also one of the best way to keep some of your best hacks well designed and organized for further consultation.
I dont see myself blogging often because  my intention are mainly to keep some of my opensource work together but i hope the little will be more meaningful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After few days of looking around some blogging services i decided that i will settle with &lt;a href=&quot;http://pages.github.com&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt; mostly because it was recommended by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quora.com/Whats-the-best-blogging-platform-for-programmers&quot;&gt;Quora Programming Community&lt;/a&gt; but also i wanted to become familiar with github markdown but i was  lazy to learn them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After  googling for a while  i realized that to have a decent blog won`t be only wrapping text with markdown synthax but involving templates so i gave  a try   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2014/08/build-blog-jekyll-github-pages/&quot;&gt; Barry Clark&lt;/a&gt; tutorials on how to get started with   Jekyll and Github Pages and i found it to be simple and easy  but as everything else,it requires attention if you want your pages to be rendered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, As you could guess,this was my first post,testing markdown and Jekyll.I hope to write about my experience with Jekyll/Github Pages soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JA MATTA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://eliethesaiyan.github.io/hello-world</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eliethesaiyan.github.io/hello-world</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>