<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MAGAMBO Gatete Elie</title>
    <description>Data Scientist/Software Engineer</description>
    <link>http://eliethesaiyan.github.io</link>
    <atom:link href="http://eliethesaiyan.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Fixing Broken Grub</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;i&lt;code&gt;ve never given a tought  bout blogging(I read many blogs) until i realized that i need a way to keep some of of my hacks well  organized for further reading.I always end up forgetting  how i fixed something or loosing some of the best references i&lt;/code&gt;ve seen on the internet. 
I guessed the best way to deal with those two issues i ALWAYS get is to blog about them so i could keep coming to check on them and hopefully,you,yes, you!!! you will give me an honest feedback.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided that i will settle with &lt;a href=&quot;http://pages.github.com&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt; and Jekyll mostly because they  were  highly recommended by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quora.com/Whats-the-best-blogging-platform-for-programmers&quot;&gt;Quora Programming Community&lt;/a&gt; and i also wanted to overcome my lazyness of learning how to  use markdown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After  googling for a while  i realized that to have a decent blog won`t just only be wrapping text with markdown synthax but will also templating(The Jekyll way),for simplicity reasons, i gave  a try   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2014/08/build-blog-jekyll-github-pages/&quot;&gt; Barry Clark&lt;/a&gt; tutorials on how to get started with   Jekyll and Github Pages .
I found it to be simple and easy  but as everything else,it requires attention if you want your pages to be rendered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, As you could guess,this was my first post,testing markdown and Jekyll.I hope to write about my experience with Jekyll/Github Pages soon(or never).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JA MATTA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://eliethesaiyan.github.io/:category/fixing-grub/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eliethesaiyan.github.io/:category/fixing-grub/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello Jekyll,Github Pages world</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;i`ve never seen importance of blogging(I read many blogs) until the day i realized that not only blogging is to communicate and get feedback with/from others but also one of the best way to keep some of your best hacks well designed and organized for further consultation.
I dont see myself blogging often because  my intention are mainly to keep some of my opensource work together but i hope the little will be more meaningful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After few days of looking around some blogging services i decided that i will settle with &lt;a href=&quot;http://pages.github.com&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt; mostly because it was recommended by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quora.com/Whats-the-best-blogging-platform-for-programmers&quot;&gt;Quora Programming Community&lt;/a&gt; but also i wanted to become familiar with github markdown but i was  lazy to learn them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After  googling for a while  i realized that to have a decent blog won`t be only wrapping text with markdown synthax but involving templates so i gave  a try   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2014/08/build-blog-jekyll-github-pages/&quot;&gt; Barry Clark&lt;/a&gt; tutorials on how to get started with   Jekyll and Github Pages and i found it to be simple and easy  but as everything else,it requires attention if you want your pages to be rendered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, As you could guess,this was my first post,testing markdown and Jekyll.I hope to write about my experience with Jekyll/Github Pages soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JA MATTA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://eliethesaiyan.github.io/:category/hello-world/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eliethesaiyan.github.io/:category/hello-world/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>